TUYET LE

• London, UK | ■ tuyet.a.le@hotmail.co.uk | in linkedin.com/in/toowee | • github.com/toowee-le | □ toowee.dev

SUMMARY

A highly motivated charity worker turned web developer after discovering a passion for coding. Currently transitioning via the self-taught route gaining experience building projects with HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript and Node. Udacity Front End Developer Nanodegree graduate, regular attendee at codebar and Code First Girl alumni.

SKILLS

Programming HTML · CSS · Sass · Bootstrap

JavaScript ES6+ · Node.js · Express

Tools Webpack · Git/Github · TDD · Heroku

Visual Studio Code · WordPress

Design Illustrator · InDesign · XD

Other Project Management · Research

EDUCATION & COURSES

FreeCodeCamp (Online)

Oct 2019 - current

- Currently completing the React certification
- Completed <u>Responsive Web Design</u> and <u>JavaScript</u> <u>Algorithms & Data Structures</u> certifications

Udacity Front End Web Developer Nanodegree (Online) *Mar – Sept 2020*

Built 5 projects with HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript,
Node.js/Express, Webpack, Service Workers and APIs

Code First Girls & Goldman Sachs - Python Programming *Feb - Apr 2020*

- Pair programming with 3 other team members to learn Python using PyCharm
- Built a cocktail recipe finder back-end app with Python and a public API for final course project

Code First Girls - Introduction to Web Development *Oct - Dec 2019*

 Worked in a team to build a cat adoption website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery. Awarded runner-up prize for best website (Github)

Brunel University - BSc Psychology and Sociology

Sept 2011 - July 2014

First Class Honours awarded

PROJECTS

Natural Language Processing | Live Project | Github

A single-page Node-Express-Webpack web tool that analyses news articles using a text analysis API to interpret the author's emotions.

Portfolio | Live Project | Github

My personal website built with HTML, CSS/SCSS and JavaScript which showcases self-initiated projects.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Charity Administration & Finance Officer

Saving Faces - London, Mar 2017 - present

- Maintain all websites and develop web pages using semantic markup and CSS built on WordPress
- Initiated and managed the roll out of WordPress to resolve hacking issues with legacy CMS and improve front-end efficiency resulting in 10% increase in monthly traffic across all sites
- Improve charity's branding by redesigning fundraising materials for emails and print publication
- Lead social media and strategic communication meetings with research team/CEO to promote studies reaching 5000+ readers globally
- Implement Trello to streamline multiple projects and set goals improving office collaboration of 8 people
- Directly support the CEO and Trustees in the governance of the charity and chiefly manage the admin and finance department of 3 people

Honorary Clinical Researcher

Saving Faces - London, Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

- Assisted clinicians and statisticians in managing 3 major facial surgery clinical trials and audits
- Provided operational telephone support to 50+ hospitals for a new major NHS national audit
- Designed surveys with HTML to gather patient and public feedback on new clinical trials

Lead Administrator

Chobham Academy - London, Oct 2014 - Jan 2016

- Led parent outreach by launching and designing the weekly print newsletter improving parental engagement, communication and events attendance
- Maintained the primary school's CRM